PRITESH SRIVASTAVA

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/pritesh-srivastava-8903531b8 Email: priteshsrivastava502@gmail.com

Github: github.com/pritesh-55 Mobile: +91-9536962360

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Well-qualified Node.js Backend Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development and deployment requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 1+ years of related experience.

EXPERIENCE

Wozo Gaming Software Developer (Full Time)

Delhi, INDIA Sept 2023 – March 2024

• Created online slot games with a focus on designing and implementing various features such as the base game, free spins, auto play, bonus features, and expanding wilds etc. using PIXI.js Framework and TypeScript.

- o Developed game localization features allowed the games to reach a wider audience in different countries.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams- Game Art Development Team, Game Engine Development Team, RGS Integration
 Testing Team ensured the seamless integration of art assets, logic, and testing, resulting in high-quality games.
- Worked on the backend, created logic for reel strips for triggering respective game functionalities, created secured API to store
 user information with real time money balance updated for smooth interaction in game, handling API calls, API validations, RTP
 Matches and simulation code.
- Impact: Successfully delivered games to Epic Games that were well-received by a diverse international audience, leading to increased user engagement and revenue generation.
- o Skills Developed: PIXI.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Debugging, Collaboration, AWS

• **Urban Space**Backend Developer (Full Time)

Remote, INDIA

March 2023 - Aug 2023

- Responsible for the intricate backend infrastructure powering the dynamic Ecommerce platform specializing in Repairing and Installation Services.
- Designed and developed core backend components, ensuring seamless functionality and an excellent user experience. Collaborated closely with frontend developers who used React.js and Tailwind to create a harmonious fusion of aesthetics and functionality.
- Created and rigorously tested multiple REST APIs that serve as the backbone of the platform, connecting users with services provided by company. Meticulously crafted and maintained the server, implementing logic to translate user requests into actionable responses.
- Impact: Contributed to the success of Urban Space, making it a thriving hub for high-quality repair and installation services.
 Played a pivotal role in bringing the vision of Urban Space to life.
- o Skills Developed: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, REST API, Deployment

SKILLS SUMMARY

Languages: C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL

• Frameworks: Bootstrap, React.js, Pixi.js, Node.js, Express.js

Tools: Visual Studio, WebStorm, Git, GitHub, Postman, IntelliJ, Chrome Dev Tools, Socket.io, Docker

Platforms: Windows, Oracle, Firebase, MongoDB, Replit, Render, Vercel, Netlify, AWS

• Core Competencies: Data Structures and Algorithms, Problem Solving, Web Development, Analytical skills, Object-Oriented Programming, Technical Design, Software Development, Debugging, Frontend & Backend Development, Restful API Development, Serverful & Serverless Deployment, Monolithic & Microservices Architecture, Load Balancing, CI/CD Pipelines.

EDUCATION

ABES Engineering College

Bachelor of Technology | GPA: 7.2

Ghaziabad, INDIA Aug 2019 - June 2023

Courses: Operating Systems, Data Structures, Analysis of Algorithms, Software Development, Networking, Databases

Divine Educational Institute *Intermediate | Percentage: 82*

Sikandrabad, INDIA April 2016 - March 2018

PROJECTS

- **Urban Space (E-Commerce Website)**: Website that is specifically tailored for Urban Space, a reputable appliances repair company serving Kharghar, Navi Mumbai. It provides a comprehensive online platform to showcase their key services, enabling customers to conveniently access their exceptional appliance repair solutions. Designed and developed core backend components, ensuring seamless functionality and an excellent user experience. Handled API calls and validations. Tech: JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, Git, REST Apis. [Code] [ProductionLink]
- Real-Time Chat App: Developed a real-time chat application using Node.js and Socket.IO to facilitate instant communication between users. Designed a responsive and intuitive user interface for seamless user experience. Demonstrated proficiency in backend development, event-driven programming, and real-time communication technologies. [Code] [DeployedLink]
- Face Recognition Web App: Effortlessly recognize faces in real-time using my JavaScript and face-api.js-powered web app. Seamlessly detects faces from webcam or video for enhanced user experience. Tech: Node.js, Express.js, JavaScript, face-api.js & HTML/CSS. [code link]

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Ranked Top 20% among active Coding Ninjas users, Achieved Expert (Level-7) status
- Back End Development & APIs Course certificate by freeCodeCamp Sept, 2023
- Rest API (Intermediate) certificate by HackerRank Sept, 2023
- Solved 500+ Algorithmic problems on various online platforms and judges.

PROFILE LINKS LINKEDIN LEETCODE HACKERRANK CODING NINJAS